<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Living Without the Bunnies</title><link>http://percival-music.ca/</link><description>Research, music, and life of Graham Percival</description><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" rel="self" href="http://percival-music.ca/rss.xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 06:26:38 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Revised website</title><link>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2018-01-09-revised-website.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Percival</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;More than five years since the last update!  Yikes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What have I been up to?  Well, I finished my PhD in May 2013, did
two post-doctoral contracts (in Singapore and Japan), then gave up
on academia and returned to Vancouver in May 2015 to work for my
brother's company, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tarsnap.com"&gt;Tarsnap Backup Inc&lt;/a&gt;.
Since then, my main focus has been my health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've made significant changes to my diet, started practicing yoga,
lifting weights, and get at least 7 hours of cardio per week.  I
fell in love with ballroom and swing dancing, and these days I
spend more time dancing than I do on music!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of music, my violin-playing has improved dramatically --
I've played in all four (main) string sections of the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://westcoastsymphony.ca/"&gt;West Coast Symphony Orchestra&lt;/a&gt;
(the best non-professional orchestra in Vancouver), and plan to
play in each section at least once per season.  I'm teaching
violin and cello, and coaching a string quartet.  I've started
composing music again (after a gap of a decade), primarily for my
students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not all good news, though.  I'm still struggling with
perfection-fueled procrastination, a la
"&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Perfect_is_the_enemy_of_good"&gt;Perfect is the enemy of good&lt;/a&gt;").
This website is a perfect example of it: 5 years ago, I decided
that I should switch to a static website generator and stop
writing in raw HTML.  That prompted an incredible number of
hesitations:  Which generator should I use?  Which markup
language?  How can I tweak the markup and/or generator to produce
the HTML I want?  Can I add a CSS file to fix stuff, or must I
edit the template's default CSS, or must I edit the template
itself?  Which web hosting provider should I use?  Does it have
HTTPS?  etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally said "enough is enough", so I'm going ahead with the
revised website right now, despite all the remaining problems.  Or
rather... I said that three days ago.  Even when I started
removing whole sections of the website (e.g., music, teaching,
software), it still took me &lt;em&gt;days&lt;/em&gt; to get this out the door!  My
plan is to make incremental updates to the website, trying to work
with "blocks of time" rather than "perfect chunks of update".
I'll pick some weekly time (say, "Wednesday morning before
teaching"), work on the website, and then upload the latest
version regardless of whether I'm fully satisfied with it or not.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bunnies</category><guid>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2018-01-09-revised-website.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 21:31:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Artifastring 2.0</title><link>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2012-11-22-artifastring-2.0.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Percival</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;After over a year of development, I have released Artifastring 2.0.
This includes higher-quality output, an incredible amount of
optimizations (up to 100x realtime), and now has multiple distinct
instrument sounds: 5 different violins, 2 viola, and 3 cellos.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://percival-music.ca/artifastring/"&gt;http://percival-music.ca/artifastring/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the speed improvements are thanks to the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://eigen.tuxfamily.org"&gt;Eigen&lt;/a&gt; C++ template library for linear
algebra. In particular, this enabled me to easily write SIMD code rather
than using floats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other bits of interest are the realtime OSC server and an interface for
the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://charlie-roberts.com/Control/"&gt;Control (OSC)&lt;/a&gt; app. Users
with iOS or Android tablets can control the physical modelling with
their fingers! I'm hoping to have a video in a few days, although I
still need to find somebody with a video camera. Before you get too
excited, I should add that this is a proof-of-concept of the
communication between tablet and computer; I haven't put any thought
towards the actual GUI or ease of control. My focus is on finishing my
thesis, so if anybody is interested in making better interfaces, go
nuts!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's sure to be rough edges left in this release. I'm trying to force
myself to accept "the perfect is the enemy of the good". I'm having huge
problems writing my thesis because whenever I write down what I've done,
I think of possible flaws, which immediately prompts me to spend a week
or two performing experiments which justify what I've done (or else
demonstrate a real problem, in which case I spend another week or two
changing even more!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, I expect a 2.2 release to happen within the next
month or two. Of course, if more people test the 2.0 version and report
problems, I'll have more confidence (and more motivation!) to get the
2.2 release out there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bunnies</category><guid>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2012-11-22-artifastring-2.0.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2012 01:06:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Ubuntu ssh agent admitted failure</title><link>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2011-08-28-ubuntu-ssh.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Percival</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Ubuntu 10.04 LTS has a serious bug in ssh/ssh-agent/something which
causes it to fail to log in to a system even if you have your ssh
identies set up. This caused me an hour of panic before I found a
workaround. I'm putting it here in case somebody else has the same
problem and google finds this for them. (tl;dr: use
&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;SSH_AUTH_SOCK=0sshfoo.bar.baz&lt;/tt&gt; )&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I swap between two laptops and a desktop regularly. I have a shared
dotfiles git repository, so my normal settings are fine -- but that
won't work for stuff like email passwords, or even email. My current
setup is to use an sd card for personal stuff. (yes, my stuff is in an
encrypted loop-back partition on that card; I'm not crazy!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days ago (just after returning to Glasgow), I started having read
errors on the card. This was particularly sucky because although I'd
bought a new 16gb card while in Vancouver, I hadn't gotten around to
carrying that new card, so I was using my old 8gb card. I was planning
on doing it "soon", but I definitely started to kick myself for not
getting it set up sooner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, it was only about 24 hours since I'd made a backup of the sd
card anyway, and there hadn't been any truly important emails in that
time. (I know the story should go "... but I didn't mind, because I'm
using my brother's tarsnap backup service", but it was actually about 3
days since I'd backed up in tarsnap)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, when I put the card in a different laptop, it read it just
fine. I copied stuff over, checked that things seemed ok, and then
started using the new card regularly. Everything seemed fine for a day
or two, when I discovered that I couldn't log in to various servers. At
this point, I turned to tarsnap to get a backup of my &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;ssh&lt;/tt&gt; directory,
thinking that I'd gotten some freaky bitrot in my private key but
nowhere else. No joy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But wait, it gets worse! Take a look at this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
gperciva@gperciva-desktop:~$ ssh -v strauss.elec.gla.ac.uk
OpenSSH_5.3p1 Debian-3ubuntu7, OpenSSL 0.9.8k 25 Mar 2009
debug1: Reading configuration data /etc/ssh/ssh_config
debug1: Applying options for *
debug1: Connecting to strauss.elec.gla.ac.uk [130.209.179.98] port 22.
...
debug1: Offering public key: /home/gperciva/.ssh/id_dsa
debug1: Server accepts key: pkalg ssh-dss blen 817
Agent admitted failure to sign using the key.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LOLwut? Server accepts key, agent admitted failure to sign in using the
key?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a bit of stumbling around, I found a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://bugs.launchpad.net/ubuntu/+source/gnome-keyring/+bug/201786"&gt;ssh bug
report&lt;/a&gt;
from 2008 in the ubuntu database. Apparently you can work around it by
setting &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;SSH_AUTH_SOCK=0&lt;/tt&gt;. You can also do some weird stuff with
something called "seahorse", but I think I'll just export the variable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bunnies</category><guid>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2011-08-28-ubuntu-ssh.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2011 09:09:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Vampire Rabbit</title><link>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2011-08-23-vampire-rabbit.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Percival</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The is the story of the Vampire Rabbit, and other bits and pieces from
my European vacation from May 2 to 23. Yes, this is a bit overdue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the timing of the first half was unfortunate -- I received the
reviewer's comments about my Vivi paper just before leaving on the
ferry. This meant that I spent the nights (after my traveling companion
had fallen asleep) making typographical corrections, hunting up more
references, and rewriting paragraphs to avoid misunderstandings. Now,
there's a long Percival tradition of doing academic work while on
vacation... but I had hoped that I'd have another 2-5 years before I
fully embraced that life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Processing the photos took a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; longer than I was expecting, and even
then, there's still a lot of mistakes in them. Mispellings (I had at
least two different ways of spelling "Ben Nevis"!), typos, wrong words,
etc. But I've already spent far too long playing with these, so I'm
reminding myself that "the perfect is the enemy of the good" and moving
on. I'll only make a few additional comments to the photos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="scotland"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Scotland&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photos:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011Glasgow"&gt;Glasgow&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011Edinburgh"&gt;Edinburgh&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011Highlands"&gt;Highlands&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011NewcastleSea"&gt;Newcastle and North
sea&lt;/a&gt;
(not scotland, but it fits in this section)&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trip began in Glasgow; my friend arrived from Vancouver. I only got
lost once while looking for the airport bus to go out and get her, but
I'd budgeted sufficient "buffer time" so that I wasn't late. The idea
was that we'd spend a few days in an English-speaking country while she
got over jetlag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We began by walking all over Glasgow (particularly the West End, where
Hogwarts is). Lest anybody doubt that I know how to show a girl a good
time, the necropolis was a big hit. Direct quote: "This is so cool!".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next day we went to Edinburgh, saw the castle, climbed Arthur's Peak,
etc. On the way back to the train station, I wanted to find a washroom,
and we ended up in the Scottish parliament debate chamber. True story! I
saw a sign for the washroom, so we went into the building, and then
security guards kept on noticing that I was looking around and seemed a
bit lost, and they all said "aye, go on around the corner / up the
stairs / through the doors", and there we were.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Driving tour of the Highlands; from Stirling to Fort Williams to Oban to
Stirling again. Saw hills, ocean, sheep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final day in Glasgow: sort out any last-minute stuff for the rest of the
trip. I bought a new travel shaver because my current one had really
dull blades; new shaver was £37 while replacement blades were £44.
Economy: 1, environment: 0? We also saw a junior (12-17 years old?)
chamber music concert. Intonation was better than we expected, but
dynamics and range of expression were worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we took the train to Newcastle-upon-Tyne. Saw the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011NewcastleSea#5635045884068735026"&gt;VAMPIRE
RABBIT&lt;/a&gt;.
Took the DHS overnight ferry to Amsterdam; an unexpectedly swanky trip.
Highly recommended! It was much better than taking an airplane for 2
hours (plus all the travel to/from airport, security, waiting at gates,
etc).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="amsterdam"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Amsterdam&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photos:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011AmsterdamCity"&gt;Amsterdam city
pictures&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011AmsterdamMonuments"&gt;Amsterdam
monuments&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011Kukenhof"&gt;Kukenhof flower
market&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011Leiden"&gt;Leiden&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011AmsterdamZoo"&gt;Amsterdam
zoo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amsterdam, city of bicycles. Deservedly famous for a huge fraction of
the population of the population cycling as their main form of
transportation. Also infamously famous for their red light district,
which my travelling companion insisted on us visiting. (also infamously
famous for marijuana, but since we've from Vancouver that wasn't
particularly notable)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We spent an hour trying to find the red light district. As we were
nearing giving up, we found a McDonalds and Burger King right next to
each other, with red neon signs. We saw the red lights! ... ok, that
wasn't the real place, but I was starting to doubt that it really
existed. We saw five "chinese message" stores. They honestly did have
massage chairs, and in one store there were people doing stuff with
somebody's feet... but I really cannot believe that Amsterdam has such a
huge market for chinese massages that it makes economic sense to have so
many stores in such a small area. I suspected that "chinese massage" was
a euphamism, but my companion insisted that she should be seeing "women
in windows" with red lights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After once again checking our two maps, cross-referencing them with a
printed guide-book, checking the compass, and walking another 15
minutes, we found the red light district. This time, there was no doubt.
It was about 9.30, so getting dark, by the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There really were red lights. I'd thought that "red light district" was
just a phrase, but no -- there were individual "store fronts", lit with
a red neon florescent bulb above the door and window. And in the window
(actually, often the door), was a woman in "underwear". Often shaking or
grinding, sometimes tapping the door to attract attention. It was...
well, the first word that comes to mind is "tacky". Certainly not sexy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, there was one "store front" which attracted my attention --
it did not have a woman cavorting about. Instead, there was a blond
woman sitting on a bed, wearing glases, and reading a book. I'm fairly
certain that the glasses were fake and the "intellectual" facade was a
sham -- but at least somebody was &lt;em&gt;pretending&lt;/em&gt; to be classy. And no, I
didn't see any women with cat ears. Now *that* would have gotten my
attention!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that we didn't make an extensive tour. We passed about half a dozen
windows on our way into the central red light district, and then we saw
a group of seniors in a tour group. We followed them for a bit; this
group was circling a big old chuch smack in the middle of the red light
district. My travelling companion thought that it really was a church
tour group, but I pointed out that if they were honestly there to see
the church, they'd have gone in the daylight, not at night. I mean,
there were red lights just opposite the street from the chrurch, clearly
visible from where they were. After circling the church, we stopped
stalking the senior's travel group, and walked back to our hotel. We
passed another half dozen windows along the way. No, we didn't stop for
any of the live sex shows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, it was more weird than anything else. I didn't feel unsafe
-- granted we left the area before 10pm, but the whole place still felt
quite regulated and well-policed. And I certainly approve of having a
safe place for this kind of thing! But it's not quite my scene, just
like a football match isn't my scene. (I'm sure that the Amsterdam red
light district is much safer than a British football match, though!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day we saw a bunch of museums, and stopped for dinner at a
"bergermeester", where I had a "meester biefburger" with "dragonmayo".
It was absolutely gigantic (even by North American standards!), and I
wasn't certain if I would eat it or if it would eat me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Went to Kukenhof, saw flowers. Not being female, that's about all I can
say about the place. :) After that, we went to the Concertgebouw. Saw a
string quartet, not impressed. They played Haydn like Haydn (clean,
together, careful, fussy, uninspired). The played Beethoven like Haydn.
They played Debussy like Beethoven (some expression, moderate rubato,
taking some risks, not always together but that's ok). No visible
communication between the players; I suspect the Haydn and Beethoven was
really together because they'd played it a lot and knew exactly what
everybody was going to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saw the zoo. Protip: reserve a whole day. We could only spend the
morning there due to train ticket reservations, and regretted it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="brussels"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Brussels&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photos:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011BrusselsCity"&gt;Brussels
city&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011BrusselsMonuments"&gt;Brussels
monuments&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011Bruges"&gt;Bruges&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011Ghent"&gt;Ghent&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011BrusselsMuseums"&gt;Brussels
museums&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011Antwerp"&gt;Antwerp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brussels wasn't as nice as Amsterdam. It's famous for fries (with
mayonaise), but the two or three places we tried fries weren't
particularly special. I mean, they were better than McDonalds fries, but
that doesn't exactly say much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saw the Musical Instrument Museum. That was neat, and they even had a
bunch of old electronic instruments in the basement! That was a very
nice touch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really fancy churches. Protip: if you want to see art, don't bother with
museums or galleries; just wander into a nearby church. Doesn't have to
be a big cathedral; they all have fancy artwork.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did a bunch of short trips to surrounding towns/villages/cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="paris"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Paris&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photos:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011ParisCity"&gt;Paris
city&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011ParisMonuments"&gt;Paris
monuments&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011ParisMuseums"&gt;Paris
museums&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011ParisCemeteries"&gt;Paris
cemeteries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were met at the train station by one of the LilyPond developers. He
very kindly showed us around the town, translated, and gave us the
"inside view" of the city! We got plenty of exercise walking around
Paris.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We met with other LilyPond developers (plus some of their girlfriends --
that is, the girlfriends of some LilyPond developers. I haven't heard of
any of them having more than one girlfriend!). It was really neat
"putting faces to the names".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to seeing the big sites, we visited a cemetery. I really
liked the cemeteries in France when I visited in 1997, so I insisted
that we go to one this time. Not for any kind of macabre reason, or any
kind of "omg this famous person is buried here" reason -- I just like
the fancy graves as pieces of scuplture/architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="south-england"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;South England&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photos:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011EnglandDover"&gt;Dover&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011EnglandDriving"&gt;Miscellaneous pictures from driving
around&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011EnglandRye"&gt;Rye&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011EnglandSteyning"&gt;Steyning&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011EnglandAmberley"&gt;Amberley&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011EnglandSwanage"&gt;Swanage&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011EnglandCorfecastle"&gt;Corfe
castle&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011EnglandLondon"&gt;London&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We met up with a friend and he drove us around southern England,
starting from the ferry to Dover. We stopped to admire a few extremely
picturesque villages and wild ponies, then arrived at the Dorsets area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the morning we saw the really cool &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011EnglandCorfecastle#5641596765992307426"&gt;Durdle
door&lt;/a&gt;,
then continued driving around, ending up at London for the night. In the
morning, we briefly saw the really big tourist stuff (Buckingham palace,
Westminister Abbey, parliament buildings, big ben, etc).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Returning to Glasgow was a pain. I dropped off my companion at Heathrow
at 14:30, and then took the underground back to London Euston -- only to
discover that the train had been cancelled due to high winds in the
Scottish Borders area! Instead, I was to take a train up to Edinburgh
(from King's Cross), then get a train from Edinburgh to Glasgow. But
halfway along that trip, we were told that the train would end in
Newcastle, and we should wait for the next train (which &lt;em&gt;would&lt;/em&gt; be
continuing up to Edinbrugh).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, I only got back to my flat at midnight. It normally takes
about 5 hours to go from London to Glasgow, not 11.5 hours! But I
arrived eventually, exhausted but happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tentative plan for next year: Berlin, Zurich, Vienna, Prague.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bunnies</category><guid>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2011-08-23-vampire-rabbit.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 12:25:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Becoming social</title><link>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2011-07-13-becoming-social.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Percival</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Following &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://xkcd.com/918/"&gt;xkcd #918&lt;/a&gt;, I have joined google+.
What's google+? To paraphrase that brilliant webcomic, "it's like
facebook, but it's not facebook".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's an important distinction if you have any privacy, moral, or
pragmatic concerns. Facebook is a bad company. Their "walled garden"
approach -- in terms of users' private data, as well as applications and
casual browsing -- does actual harm to the idea of a global internet.
Even if you have no romantic or philosophical notions of the "flow of
information", such walled gardens are simply harmful on a practical
level. When (not if) something unquestionably better than facebook comes
around, you'll lose a lot of data if you use facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(why am I certain that something better than facebook will arrive?
That's simply the history of computing. Every software project is
supplanted eventually; thinking that software XYZ is the pinnacle of
human-computer interaction is the sheerest folly. Something better than
facebook, something better than google+, something better than mutt or
vim or python, is always bound to happen. Maybe not in 5 years or 10 or
20 years, but it &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; happen)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, you can "plus me" (if that's the verb we're going to use)
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://plus.google.com/?tab=XX#107782479450604073806/about"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
Invitations available for people I know who want to join.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bunnies</category><guid>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2011-07-13-becoming-social.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 19:40:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Artifastring 1.6</title><link>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2011-06-27-artifastring-1.6.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Percival</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Artifastring 1.6 is now out. This adds a fancier violin model, scripts
to simplify creating images and video from an .actions file, and a
switch to the autotools build system.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://percival-music.ca/artifastring/"&gt;http://percival-music.ca/artifastring/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were 44 commits between the release-1.4 and release-1.6 tags, with
lots more info in the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/gperciva/artifastring/commits/master"&gt;git
changelog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully this will be the last Artifastring release before Vivi 1.0
(within the next week). After that, expect not much in July. August will
hopefully see Artifastring being expanded to cover cello, viola, and
maybe even multiple violins. This relies on a Masters project at the
University of Glasgow, so it's not under my control.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bunnies</category><guid>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2011-06-27-artifastring-1.6.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2011 20:54:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>ccbeamer 0.2</title><link>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2011-06-26-ccbeamer-0.2.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Percival</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I found a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.hartwork.org/?p=52"&gt;nice set of Creative Commons logos for
LaTeX&lt;/a&gt;, but they were used with
&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;\input{cc_beamer}&lt;/tt&gt;. Following advice in a comment at that blog, I've
turned them into a LaTeX package. Following the spirit of open source --
not to mention the CC-SA license itself -- here's the source code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://percival-music.ca/blogfiles/ccbeamer-0.2.zip"&gt;ccbeamer-0.2.zip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that although the hartwork blog has a general "CC-no derivative
works, unless otherwise expressly stated", the actual zip file states
that it is under CC-SA 3.0.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bunnies</category><guid>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2011-06-26-ccbeamer-0.2.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2011 19:54:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>LilyPond 2.14 is out</title><link>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2011-06-11-lilypond-2.14.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Percival</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm happy to announce the release of GNU LilyPond 2.14. LilyPond is a
music engraving program, devoted to producing the highest-quality sheet
music possible. It brings the aesthetics of traditionally engraved music
to computer printouts. Many improvements have been made in the past two
and a half years since the previous main stable version. (yes, that's a
long time between stable versions!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="lilypond-is-doing-great-lilypond-is-headed-for-disaster"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;LilyPond is doing great! LilyPond is headed for disaster!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On one hand, we're doing great. The new stable version 2.14.0 is finally
out, we've finally started the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lilypond.org/~graham/gop/"&gt;Grand Organization
Project&lt;/a&gt; to resolve various
administrative problems, and there are no huge problems which will stop
us from releasing 2.16.0 in a few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, we still have far too many tasks concentrated in far
too few people. This is not healthy, both for the individuals doing the
work, but also for the project as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sustainable-development-in-software-projects"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;"Sustainable development" in software projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every person will leave the LilyPond project sooner or later. Our lives
change, our hobbies shift, and unfortunately our health and lifespans
are not infinite. What would happen if, for example, I decided that my
PhD thesis and future career were more important than LilyPond and that
I should drop out the project?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(this is not an idle question; I honestly &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; quit LilyPond. Some
open-source volunteering would still be good for my career, but it would
be much more benefitial for me to spend that time on
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://marsyas.info/"&gt;Marsyas&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://chuck.cs.princeton.edu/"&gt;ChucK&lt;/a&gt;, or even
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ccrma.stanford.edu/software/stk/"&gt;STK&lt;/a&gt; instead. Those
project are much more aligned with my research and potential
tenure-track jobs, and I would learn much more by working on them
instead of LilyPond.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such problems are charmingly referred to a project's &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bus_factor"&gt;Bus
factor&lt;/a&gt;: how many people
would need to be hit by a bus before the project falls into disarray?
LilyPond has a quite low bus factor -- losing as few as three people
would cause massive problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gave a
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://percival-music.ca/blog/2010-08-01-sustainable-development.html"&gt;presentation&lt;/a&gt;
at RMLL 2010 about this last year, and I was reminded of this by a
recent &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blogs.gnome.org/bolsh/2011/05/31/effective-mentoring-programs/"&gt;discussion about mentoring
efforts&lt;/a&gt;
by a gnome developer looking at the approximate 25% success rate (over a
variety of projects, including LilyPond).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="decentralization"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Decentralization&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A low "bus factor" means that work (or knowledge or power) is highly
concentrated in a few people. It's much better for the project if
work/knowledge/power is distributed more evenly -- losing one person
will cause fewer problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other benefits to decentralization, of course. A lower
workload on "central" people will lessen burn-out, which may encourage
them to stick around for longer. That can, in turn, lessen the workload
on other people: there are many cases where an "old-timer" can make a
few suggestions in a 5-minute email which save a new contributor
literally hours of work and frustration. Everybody wins!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="dangers-of-burn-out"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Dangers of burn-out&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm (in)famous on the LilyPond mailing lists for arguing against new
proposals. "We don't have the resources / nice idea, but wait until... /
you can do that with a user .ly file / etc".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some cases this is due to my subscribing in a certain philosophy of
design: &lt;em&gt;Il semble que la perfection soit atteinte non quand il n'y a
plus rien à ajouter, mais quand il n'y a plus rien à retrancher.&lt;/em&gt;
(perfection is finally attained not when there is no longer anything to
add, but when there is no longer anything to take away; from &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Antoine_de_Saint_Exup%C3%A9ry"&gt;quotes
from Antoine de Sainte
Exupéry&lt;/a&gt;).
A similar idea was mentioned by Steve Jobs in a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blogs.forbes.com/carminegallo/2011/05/16/steve-jobs-get-rid-of-the-crappy-stuff/"&gt;recent
interview&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
People think focus means saying yes to the thing you've got to focus
on. But that's not what it means at all. It means saying no to the
hundred other good ideas that there are. You have to pick carefully.
I'm actually as proud of the things we haven’t done as the things I
have done. Innovation is saying 'no' to 1,000 things.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the other part is that I simply don't want more work. Every single
time that somebody comes up to me with an excited new idea, it breaks my
heart because my first thought is "oh boy, now I need to express polite
enthusiasm". It doesn't matter if it's over email, in a chat, in a
meeting, or in a private conversation. Doesn't matter if it's from a
longtime developer or an unknown user. Doesn't matter if I think it's a
brilliant idea, an obvious but useful improvement, or a pie-in-the-sky
ludicrous concept. My first thought is always the same: "bleh, more
work".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the moment, I'm committed to doing 10 hours of LilyPond work per
week. I've "saved up" a few hours from the previous two months
(including my vacation) because I knew that I'd be busier after 2.14
came out -- at the time of this writing, I have 12 hours of LilyPond
time left. Each Monday morning, I add 10 hours to that figure. By my
estimation, only considering the published &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lilypond.org/doc/v2.13/Documentation/contributor/grand-organization-project-_0028gop_0029"&gt;Grand Organization
Project&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lilypond.org/doc/v2.13/Documentation/contributor/grand-lilypond-input-syntax-standardization-_0028gliss_0029"&gt;Grand LilyPond Input Syntax
Standardization&lt;/a&gt;
backlogs, I won't be able to do make any LilyPond bugfixes or new
features of my own until the end of 2011. My entire time will be spent
organizing and helping other people to do work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="you-can-help"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;You can help&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get involved! Anything that makes LilyPond less centralized will help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if it has nothing to do with me personally, there will probably be
a "trickle up" effect from reducing the burden of other people. For
example, if a translator started doing some of the work of Francisco
(the Translation Meister), he would have more time to investigate
problems himself instead of asking me to help. Similarly, if a developer
offers to seriously mentor one or two new programmers, that might mean
one or two fewer programmers who come to me for help because everybody
else is ignoring them. If you're a new contributor, then spend some
extra time talking to other new contributors -- provide moral support
and somebody to commiserate with, even if you can't discuss anything
technical!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for me personally... I spend about 2 hours a week on completely
mindless administration. Stuff that could almost be done by a computer
program. I could easily write 5 or 6 sentences on paper, and somebody
could follow those blindly. For example, twice a week I send a "patches
countdown" email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;go to the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://code.google.com/p/lilypond/issues/list?can=2&amp;amp;q=label:patch%20patch=review&amp;amp;sort=patch&amp;amp;colspec=ID%20Type%20Status%20Priority%20Stars%20Owner%20Patch%20Summary"&gt;list of patches for
review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pick two or three issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;find the codereview URL inside the issue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;click on that link&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if there are any reviews, check that the last review is not negative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;include the subject line and link to the codereview page in an email
to lilypond-devel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All I need to offload this task is a reliable person who doesn't mind a
bit of boredom offering to do it. 15 minutes, twice a week. If there's
anything unusual, I'm happy to discuss it (and possibly modify the
instructions to handle such cases). But I'm not asking for any knowledge
or creativity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other tasks which &lt;em&gt;would&lt;/em&gt; require knowledge and/or creativity.
For example, many people ask for a changelog -- what's new in each
release? If somebody is interested in lilypond development, they could
spend 1-2 hours a week reading the developer email list and the git
changelog, then writing a 3-4 sentence summary for each release. That
would be a nice "gentle" introduction to how things work, and it would
benefit many users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, there are some tasks which are regular weekly affairs, and
others which are one-time. Here's a great non-really-technical one-time
task: our list of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lilypond.org/doc/v2.15/Documentation/contributor/major-release-checklist"&gt;places to send release announcements
to&lt;/a&gt;
is quite old. Half of the links don't work. So I haven't bothered to
make any release announcements (other than our own webpage) at all. If
somebody wanted to spread the word, they could spend 2-5 hours looking
for relevant places to announce lilypond, maybe asking for other
suggestions from lilypond-user, and make a nice list. Then either send
our release announcement to those places himself, or else ask me to do
it. I wouldn't mind doing it as long as all the links work and I don't
need to hunt around to find out how to send the announcement (i.e. give
me a specific link to the announcement form, not a generic link to the
main website!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="square-pegs-into-round-holes"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Square pegs into round holes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past, we haven't done a good job of organizing people in
LilyPond. Some people are suited to regular work; other people are
suited to one-time jobs. Some people like technical challenges and
creative freedom; other people prefer a rigid set of guidelines so they
know that they're not making any mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need people for all sorts of tasks, and over the next few weeks, I'm
really going to try to make sure that everybody has a job that suits
them. We've lost a lot of potential effort by asking people to do tasks
which don't really appeal to them, and then not having those jobs "open"
when another person offers to help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bunnies</category><guid>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2011-06-11-lilypond-2.14.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2011 15:10:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Vivi's first academic publication: SMC 2011</title><link>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2011-05-27-smc2011-paper.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Percival</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first paper about Vivi was published in the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://smc2011.smcnetwork.org"&gt;Sound and Music
Conference 2011&lt;/a&gt;. It is published
under a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org"&gt;Creative Commons&lt;/a&gt; license:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://percival-music.ca/research/percival-smc2011.pdf"&gt;percival-smc2011.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other news, I'm still working on the refactoring of the source code.
I barely got any work done during my 3-week vacation, which I guess
could be considered to be a good thing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll be making some posts about general-interest parts of the vacation
over the next few days or weeks, but at the moment my focus has to be
work. I spent 3 days in bed (almost) recovering from exhaustion, so I've
got even more work to catch up on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bunnies</category><guid>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2011-05-27-smc2011-paper.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 13:36:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Artifastring 1.4</title><link>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2011-04-06-artifastring-1.4.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Percival</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Artifastring 1.4 is now out (now including video output!), along with
a heartwarming story: another person is working on this project!
Welcome to Marcos Press ("tdy")!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://percival-music.ca/artifastring/"&gt;http://percival-music.ca/artifastring/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I introduced Vivi to the &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;lilypond-user&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt; mailing list, sparking a long
discussion, on both the technical accomplishments of Vivi and the
musical implications of such work. But in the middle of it, I received a
very kind offer of a violin model in &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blender.org"&gt;blender&lt;/a&gt;.
Blender is a Free 3D content creation suite; amonst other things, it can
create animations. I was using that for Vivi already, but only with very
primitive output -- 4 cylinders for the strings, 1 cylinder for the bow,
cones for the fingers, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He sent along an image of the violin, and it looked quite nice. So I
wrote back to say that I was very interested, and did he also have a bow
model?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He replied that he didn't have a bow model yet, but that he'd do it
right away, because the bow was easier to do than a violin. A few hours
later, he sent me a file with both models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The small picture I saw earlier did not do it justice. His models were
literally jaw-dropping. It includes a sound post. It includes the wires
attaching the tailpiece to the knob at the bottom of the violin. It
includes curved f-holes. The strings have different colors of windings.
The tailpiece has actual holes -- or rather, not just circular holes,
but correctly-shaped holes -- into which the strings fit. The bridge has
notches in which the strings fit. Ditto for the nut. The strings wind
around the tuning pegs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The below picture doesn't do it justice, either... I should have rotated
the violin a bit more so that you could see more details of the bridge.
But spending the whole blog post talking about a video without showing
any graphics would be a bit weird.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://percival-music.ca/blogfiles/vivi-video.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Frame from video" src="http://percival-music.ca/blogfiles/vivi-video.jpg" style="width: 50.0%;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (click to enlarge)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I got the file, I must have spent about 30 minutes just looking at
the model. Zooming in, zooming out, rotating... everywhere I looked,
there was an incredible amount of detail. I need to learn how to make a
"fly-by animation" in blender, to show off all the pieces of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The model also included some text inside the violin, like a "maker's
mark". I didn't notice it for the first 20 minutes or so, but when I
read it, I almost cried.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;em&gt;from tdy's 1st
blender modeling
for Graham Persival
Vivi System
Vivi's 2nd Violin
Loving OpenSource
2011&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I've been working on open-source projects for a long time... since
2003, actually. I've released my own software as open source. At times,
I've spent over 60 hours a week on existing open-source projects. I've
trained approximately 30 people to do documentation work (admittely,
about half of them just read the guidelines I wrote and didn't need any
further guidance). I've directly caused literally hundreds of hours of
work, mostly on LilyPond. I've reviewed patches, mentored new
contributors, and seen those contributors to become much more
knowledgeable than me and tell me off for things (that's my favorite
part of mentoring :). I've had people express interest in work that I'd
abandoned, and I passed the source code along to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this is the first time that somebody's sent a contribution to one of
my own projects, and it's a whole new feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also feel even more inspired to make Vivi better -- with Marcos' work,
the sound quality is much worse than the video quality. I need to
improve her bow control much more. I was already planning on doing that,
of course, but now I have even more motivation. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Here's an example of the videos it produces:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://percival-music.ca/video/black-box.mpeg"&gt;Black-box testing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So again, Marcos -- thank you so much! To other people: I've got a
github repository now, and more bits and pieces will be coming in the
next few days. What are you waiting for? :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/gperciva/artifastring"&gt;https://github.com/gperciva/artifastring&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bunnies</category><guid>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2011-04-06-artifastring-1.4.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 10:58:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>