<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Living Without the Bunnies</title><link>http://percival-music.ca/</link><description>Research, music, and life of Graham Percival</description><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" href="http://percival-music.ca/rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 22:47:27 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Japan trip</title><link>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2018-04-16-japan-trip-reflections.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Percival</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had a great time in Japan last month!  But it's always worth
noting what I can learn for future trips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Take notes at the end of each day!  At the end of a trip, I'm
exhausted (and often get sick), so it can be difficult to
remember all the stories and remarks I wanted to share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(For example, the Japan trip ended almost a full month ago, and
I've only now finished the blog post about it.  And I still know
that I've forgotten to mention some neat stuff!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Either reserve more time for resting, or make better plans ahead
of time.  Before the trip, I was focused on getting some work
done for the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://wcams.ca/"&gt;West Coast Amateur Musicians Society summer music
camp&lt;/a&gt;, so it was a bit of a scramble to
figure out what I'd do in Osaka and Kyoto in particular.
Travelling with my Japanese friends was great because one of
them made the plans.  :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Improve my Japanese.  Before going back to Japan, I should be
able to read the common food-related kanji, and to be able to
ask if I can have a dish without the meat and fish (if it's a
sympathetic restaurant, like a natural food store).  Not having
to worry about finding vegetarian food would be a huge relief!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;There were really famous places I didn't see, such as
Kiyomizu-dera and Kinkau-ji in Kyoto.  More time in Osaka and
Kyoto is definitely called for!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;That said, the things that I enjoyed the most were more the
"ordinary" things: watching a train conductor pointing at things
and saying stuff, hearing the Kansai dialect, the animal cafe,
and of course the Meetup group party.  So even though I'm quite
aware that there's more things to see in all the cities I
visited, I'm not disappointed that I didn't get to see them yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not certain if I'll try to visit next year, or wait two years.
It depends on how works goes, and how much I improve my Japanese
in the next 6 months.  I definitely don't want to wait 3 years,
though!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bunnies</category><guid>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2018-04-16-japan-trip-reflections.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 15:35:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan trip</title><link>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2018-03-19-japan-trip.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Percival</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="section" id="first-trip-in-3-years"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;First trip in 3 years&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to Japan from March 7 to 19, and had a great time!  I've
finally written about it, as well as added text to my
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://photos.app.goo.gl/vfs6ZGMfVTOlPKe92"&gt;Japan photo album&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(If you want to see the comments I added to the photos (about 90%
of them), click the "i" icon in the top-right corner of the
photos).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trip was officially so that I could attend the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2018.asiabsdcon.org/"&gt;AsiaBSDCon 2018&lt;/a&gt; conference as a
Tarsnap employee with my boss Colin, although I extended the 2-day
conference into 12 days in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="day-0"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Day 0&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The flight went very well -- I was upgraded from premium economy
to business class!  This was a 787 plane, so that meant incredible
luxury: the seat could lie down completely flat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As soon as we stepped out from customs at Narita, a TV news team
asked to interview us.  We think it was "Youは何しに日本へ？"
("why did you come to Japan?").  Since I was well-rested, I
agreed.  There was 1 interviewer, 1 cameraman, and 1 translator.
I spoke in Japanese whenever possible... maybe half the time I
could answer the question without waiting for the translator.
Granted, these were very basic questions: How long are you
visiting Japan?  What will you see?  etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the usual airport errands (getting a data SIM card and
transit passes), we travelled by train to my boss' hotel in Tokyo
(close to Ichigaya station).  Unfortunately there were no
vacancies there when I was booking my hotels... although I suspect
that there actually &lt;em&gt;were&lt;/em&gt; spaces available, but they'd been
reserved by the conference and I didn't realize that I could have
booked through them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, after checking in (in Japanese) my boss into his hotel, I
set off towards my hotel.  I knew it was roughly east-north-east
from my current position, and the area was bounded by a canal on
the west and north, and a major street on the east.  So even
though my phone's GPS hadn't figured out my position, I faced east
and started walking.  What could go wrong?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, apparently I was facing south, not east -- The only
direction that wasn't bounded by an obvious "you've gone too far"
landmark.  I realized something was wrong when I reached Kojimachi
station, which wasn't on my printed-out map at all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Aside: google maps won't download maps for Japan due to some kind
of contractual issue, and my boss had the data SIM card, not me.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I stopped at a convenience store and asked for directions back
to Ichigaya station.  15 minutes after asking for directions, I
was back at my starting place, and a further 15 minutes later I
arrived at my hotel.  45 minutes of walking around carrying my
suitcase (because I didn't want to annoy people around me with the
noise of the wheels) wasn't exactly how I planned on spending my
first night in Tokyo.  But hey, I've been meaning to improve my
arm strength!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="part-1-tokyo"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Part 1: Tokyo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="day-1"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Day 1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For breakfast at 4am, I got my typical Japanese meal: convenience
store sandwiches, a diet coke, and a doughnut-type baked good.
Melonpan (basically bread + sugar, with a criss-cross pattern on
top) is a particular favourite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I stopped drinking diet coke two years ago, and stopped eating
sugar a year ago.  But I figured that since I was on vacation, it
was ok.  Also, it was somewhat nostalgic!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;((Yes, food is a problem for me in Japan.  I'm vegetarian, and
that's not common over there.  I mean, in BC over 10% of the
population is vegetarian or vegan, so almost every restaurant will
have at least one vegetarian dish.  That's not the case in
Japan!))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, I walked to Colin's hotel, then we walked to the conference
venue, then I walked to Akihabara station.  A nice little 6.7km
walk to begin the day!  (There were two days of "pre-conference"
that I wasn't attending, but my boss was.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent the rest of the morning window shopping, stopped at an
Indian restaurant for lunch (they always have a vegetarian dish,
so it's easy!), then more window shopping.  There seem to have
been relatively few really popular new anime in the past few
years.  But it's always fascinating to see the variety of goods
that are available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I returned to my hotel around 2pm to sleep.  Around 7pm I got up
and went to a Japanese curry place for dinner.  I managed the
entire conversation with the waitress in Japanese!  I was really
happy with myself for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="day-2"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Day 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I began by taking the train to Shibuya, although I got off one
station early so I could wander around the streets.  I wanted to
see the Shinjuku Gyoen National Garden, but it wasn't open!  It
wasn't clear if it was just that entrance that was closed, or
whether it would open in a few hours, or what.  I opted to
continue walking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About five minutes later, I realized that I was in the "dangerous"
part of Shinjuku -- there's some sketchy places on the east side
of the tracks.  Fortunately, it didn't seem bad at 8am, so I kept
to the middle of the street and passed through without incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw Meiji jinju, with some lovely morning mist rising off the
pavement in the park.  Unfortunately the main shrine was
undergoing some renovations -- the chainsaw noise kind-of ruined
the peace of the shrine.  The surrounding woods were nice, though!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then spent two hours in Harajuku looking for socks.  One of my
friends in Vancouver wanted some tabi (socks with a separation
between the big toe and the other toes, ideal for sandals).  Those
were easy to find... but socks for her kids?!  Not easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At 11:30am I gave up and had lunch (again at an Indian restaurant,
but somewhat by accident -- I was looking through the side streets
off from Takashita-dori, and it looked very un-crowded).  I
decided to give up on the socks, and head directly back to the
station.  But by chance, I passed a sock store, which had a whole
rack of children's socks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, I went to Nakano Broadway.  What did I find, 4 stores
away from the station?  Another sock store, of course.  Sigh.
After another session of looking around, I headed back to my hotel
to sleep for 3 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That evening we had a business dinner: one of my boss' internet
(and business) friends lives in Tokyo.  We went to "Salt", a fancy
restaurant on the sixth floor of the Marunouchi building (right
next to Tokyo station).  Unfortunately they'd changed their menu
so the one they had online was out of date -- they no longer had a
vegetarian main course, so that meal was slightly uncomfortable.
Oh well, it was fun listening to the discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="day-3"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Day 3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the first day of the full conference.  I'd estimate 50-70
people there?  There were two "tracks" (meaning two talks
happening at the same time, in different rooms).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happily, the conference lunch included vegetarian bento boxes!
They were very colourful, delicious, and blessedly easy to eat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colin's talk went well:
- &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.daemonology.net/papers/bootprofiling.pdf"&gt;Profiling the FreeBSD kernel boot PDF&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NeJ2ztPasso"&gt;Presentation video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were both tired at this point, so we had some pizza at an
Italian restaurant for dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="day-4"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Day 4&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second day of the conference.  Many of the talks were not
particularly in my area of interest -- lots of talks about bhyve
(a virtualization layer), which I've never used.  Still, it was
nice to see people talking enthusiastically about their area of
expertise.  It made me want to do some more advanced work of my
own, and present it at this conference next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One slight disappointment is that I would have liked to have
talked to more Japanese people.  I introduced myself to two people
(in Japanese), but generally the conference-goers seemed to split
into clusters of Japanese, and clusters of Europeans.  I can
understand why -- it's daunting to try to talk in a second or
third language, and many of the Europeans had quite accented
voices which would make it much harder for Japanese speakers to
understand (since their exposure is to American English, with a
bit of British thrown in).  The next time I attend this
conference, I'll try to be more fearless about speaking in
Japanese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="day-5-part-1"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Day 5 part 1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got Colin back to the airport line, then went to Tokyo station
to figure out my next step.  Tokyo station is a zoo!  Whenever I
used it in the past, I knew exactly what I was doing --
transferring between the NEX (a different Narita airport express)
and the green line.  But this time, I wanted to stop at a vegan
restaurant in the station (yes!  A vegan restaurant in Japan!  Of
course I had to try it, and it was great.), and then I had to get
my reserved shinkansen ticket for Osaka.  That took a bit longer
than I had anticipated, but I ended up on the train I was
initially planning on getting (the 11:03 hikari train).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="part-2-shinkansen-osaka-kyoto-yokohama"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Part 2: Shinkansen, Osaka, Kyoto, Yokohama&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="day-5-part-2-osaka"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Day 5 part 2: Osaka&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shinkansen announcer used a British accent!  Much nicer to
hear than the American accent on the Tokyo trains.  (That said,
Christelle's voice isn't bad!  I'm just not a fan of the
California accent.)  Incidentally, you should be entirely
unsurprised to hear that there's a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xs24fCftDGw"&gt;a youtube video of all the
train announcements for the Yamanote line&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's an incredible amount of leg room on the shinkansen, even
in the ordinary shinkansen train cars.  I'm vaguely curious to see
what the green ("business class") cars are like, because those
must be incredibly luxurious!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The average speed (including stops) was ~170 km/h (515 km in 3
hours).  Wikipedia lists the "operating speed" as 285 km/h, which
seems a bit high.  We stopped at approximately 8 stations, and
only for a few minutes each.  Maybe I just didn't notice how much
we slowed down for those stops?  The acceleration was certainly
smooth!  On more than one occasion, I didn't realize that we'd
started moving until 20-30 seconds after the train actually
started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrived at Osaka.  Half-heartedly looked at a few restaurants at
the station, but nothing looked particularly appealing (especially
given the station noise).  I ended up eating at an Indian
restaurant 5 minutes away from the station (walking towards my
hotel).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I checked into my Osaka hotel; it felt like something from the
1980s.  It actually had keys for the rooms!  I mean, not keycards!
Weird.  I was staying right next to Minamikata, which is one
subway stop south of Shin-Osaka.  It was a bit closer to the
tracks than I realized.  Or rather: I didn't realize that the
"subway" line in this area was above-ground.  (Yes, I should have
checked on google maps street view).  So it's was a bit noisier
than I'd have liked.  Granted, there's train tracks right beside
my condo at home, so it wasn't a big deal.  Just something that a
more experienced traveller would have noticed before booking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took the subway to Namba and meandered around.  It's certainly a
lively area!  It was fun for an hour during the day; I suspect
that I'd feel too out of place if I were there at night or for a
longer duration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I eventually ended up at Ashiharabashi, and took the train to
Osaka.  This was unexpectedly fun because by chance I stepped into
the first car, which had a transparent wall between the passengers
and the conductor.  I could watch him operate the train!  I think
that was the high point of the Osaka trip.  :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I meandered around the station and Yodabashi electronics store,
then took the train to Juso.  (Only one stop, but it was over a
bridge and I wasn't certain if I could walk over that bridge).
One of my childhood friends was an English teacher and lived in
this area.  I walked around a bit.  Online, I'd seen some
references to this being a "red light district", but I didn't see
many signs of that when I was walking.  Maybe 8pm was too early?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I did see a few "massage" and "Thai smile" places that had
flashing red lights around the sign.  I wondered if that was a
symbol that they offered something more... but then five minutes
later, I saw a 7-11 with the same type of flashing red lights.  So
I discarded that theory.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, there were a few cabaret bars on the other side of the train
tracks from my hotel.  I remember that this kind of thing kept on
happening in Europe, too -- red light districts tend to have
cheaper hotels than other parts of town.  Also, these districts
tend to be fairly close to train stations.  So when I'm looking
for places to stay on a hotel-search map, I tend to accidentally
pick places close to red light districts.  Maybe I'm just
desensitized to such street signs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="day-6-kyoto"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Day 6: Kyoto&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Took the shinkansen to Kyoto.  No reservation, just waved my pass
and walked straight on.  (Literally walked on -- the train was
already at the station!)  I bought a convenience store breakfast
and ate it on the train.  That's allowed!  At Kyoto, I took the
local train to Fushimi Inari Taisha (that's the famous shrine with
lots of red/orange gates).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were already a fair number of people there.  Noisy, annoying
people.  After walking up the path for about 5 minutes, I noticed
a trail heading off to the right.  I followed that, thinking it
would be a one-minute trip to a little shrine.  There was indeed
such a shrine, but the trail continued.  I spent the next 40
minutes walking up the mountain, and passed four people (plus one
dog) in the entire time.  10/10 would do again!  I ended up at a
different mountain peak first, then I backtracked slightly and
went to the main peak (and sadly rejoined the crowd).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Took the train to Demachiyanagi because I saw an advert in the
train station for a vegan-friendly Falafel restaurant in that
area.  After lunch, I walked to Higashiyama Jisho-ji, saw the
picturesque sand mound shaped like Mt. Fuji.  I found that a bit
underwhelming, but the gardens were nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took the Philosopher's Path (哲学の道), which is a walkway
beside a canal (so named because there's many temples and shrines
in the area).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stopped at a small coffee shop run by an elderly couple.  The
woman was quite talkative, and spoke in a strong Kansai dialect.
I couldn't understand most of what she said, but I recognized the
accent.  (I'm not certain if that was her real accent, or if it
was something she used for tourists -- for example, the way a
waitress at a country bar might play up a Texan accent.)  Still,
it was a neat experience to hear that accent in real life.  I
think that was my favourite part of the Kyoto portion.  :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walked to Nanzen-ji Temple.  It has an aqueduct!  A real, in-use
aqueduct!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Went to Higashiyama station, train to Nijo Castle.  Arrived at
4pm, heard warnings that I should see the inner palace first
because they closed the inner part at 4:30pm.  I walked on the
famous "Nightingale floors", which wasn't as noisy as I expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to walk west to Nijo station to take the train to the main
Kyoto station.  Unfortunately, I &lt;em&gt;again&lt;/em&gt; got my directions messed
up, and went south instead.  By the time I realized my mistake, I
was approximately equal distance from that train line and the main
Kyoto station, so I kept on walking.  (an extra 4km)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Train back to Osaka, ate omurice at the station.  A family was
sitting at the next table, and a 7-year-old (I'm guessing?) boy
said "hello" to me, but he was too shy to say anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="day-7-nagoya-and-yokohama"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Day 7: Nagoya and Yokohama&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took shinkansen again without any reservation.  While I was
looking at google maps on the train (I had the data SIM card by
this point), I noticed a "salad bowl" vegetarian restaurant in
Nagoya, so I decided to disembark and have lunch there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was a bit too early for lunch, so I wandered around a bit to
waste time.  I stopped at an Animate (anime goods store), and was
surprised to see it packed at 11am on a Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lunch was great; they put the ingredients together, then chopped
them up finely.  Most of the menu items included chicken, but
there were a few that were strictly vegetarian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I arrived at Yokohama too early to check in, but the hotel let me
drop off my suitcase.  Tried to find something vegetarian nearby,
but after 30 minutes, gave up and went to Subway.  I really need
to learn food-related kanji before my next Japan trip!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After checking in, I took the train to the main Yokohama station,
then went to the Hara model train museum.  Very impressive 30mx10m
diorama!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went up the Yokohama sky garden (273m high), saw nice views of
the city.  According to wikipedia, this 73-floor building has 79
elevators!  (By contrast, my 30-floor condo has 2 elevators.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had dinner at an Udon fast-food place at Yokohama station.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="part-3-toyama-kanazawa-tsukuba"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Part 3: Toyama, Kanazawa, Tsukuba&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the final portion of my trip, I travelled with two of my
Japanese friends.  Travelling with somebody else -- not to mention
people familiar with the local language and customs -- is a very
different experience than travelling by yourself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="day-8-toyama"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Day 8: Toyama&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I checked out at 6:40am, walked 10 minutes to the Shin-Yokohama
station, then waited for the first shinkansen at 7:03.  The train
was exactly on time, of course.  I met my friends at Tokyo station
at 7:30, and we headed off together for the last part of my Japan
trip!  We got the 8:26 shinkansen to Toyama, rented a car, and
drove to Gokayama.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gokayama is an area with traditional villages with straw huts; we
went to two villages.  I had a fantastic vegetarian meal at one of
them.  Best meal of the trip!  (I even took photos of the food.)
It was also up in the mountains, and the ground was still covered
in 30cm of snow.  Way more snow than we got in Vancouver this
year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, we drove to Chirihama beach, then drove &lt;em&gt;onto&lt;/em&gt; the
beach.  It's famous for allowing this -- the sand was very firmly
packed.  It was so weird to drive 3-4 meters away from the surf!
I think this was the first day in my life that I'd walked on snow
and sand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stayed at a ryokan (traditional Japanese hotel).  I tried
wearing geta (traditional wooden shoes with two "teeth" on the
bottom) for the first time.  At first, it was very hard to balance
myself (especially when walking up or down a slope!), but I
adapted after a few minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="day-9-toyama-and-kanazawa"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Day 9: Toyama and Kanazawa&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drove to Noto and visited the Nodojima aquarium.  Amazing sea lion
&amp;amp; dolphin show -- the sea lion followed the trainer like a puppy,
and the dolphins performed incredible tricks.  I had no idea they
could jump that far out of the water!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lunch at a "natural foods" store.  My friends asked the waitress
if my food could be vegetarian, and the restaurant was happy to
substitute tofu for the fish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drove to Kanazawa.  Stopped at a famous artisan sweets store,
where I bought some packets of sweet beans, and a jar of potato
honey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went to the 21st century museum of contemporary art.  Neat
doughnut-shaped building, with the center being a half-pool of
water.  Namely, the top looked like a small swimming pool, but the
water was less than a meter deep, and the pool had a glass bottom.
Underneath, there were museum-goers walking at the "bottom" of the
"pool".  It was interesting to see people wearing normal clothing
and walking around, apparently at the bottom of a swimming pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We dropped off the rental car and checked into the hotel.  Very
swanky place; gold trim everywhere.  Kanazawa used to be the main
spot for gold-working in Japan.  (Not mining, but rather shaping
the gold into artistic things.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dinner was at a small bar, and we met a university friend of one
of the women.  The head cook (who I think was also the owner)
lived in California for ten years, so he had good English.  (The
bar had approximately 8 tables for 4 people each, and an "open
kitchen" plan.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="day-10-kanazawa-and-tsukuba"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Day 10: Kanazawa and Tsukuba&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We began with Kanazawa castle, which is a reconstructed wooden
building.  I'd previously only seen European castles, which were
all made of stone.  This castle had a low stone wall, but the main
structure was wood, made without iron nails.  I think that most of
the load-bearing was done with diamond-shaped beams, with a few
wooden pegs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, we saw the Kenrokuen garden.  Very pretty!  There were
many trees with ropes holding the branches up -- that's to protect
the branches from snow during the winter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we walked around Nagamachi, an old district with samurai
houses and fancy crafts stores.  Much too expensive to buy
anything, but fun to look at!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shinkansen to Tokyo, train to Tsukuba.  We were then picked up and
driven to a local park by the husband of one of my friends.  When
we arrived, the other friend picked up her suitcase and ran off
(literally!).  I thought that was a bit odd, but the first woman
said that I'd be having dinner with her and her husband, so I
shrugged and said "ok".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We walked to the restaurant, went to the upper floor -- and I
discovered that they were throwing a surprise party for me!  The
woman who ran off had organized a meeting of the Japanese/English
conversation group, and she made some final preparations for the
surprise.  There were 10 people (including me) at the party, and
it was fantastic to see that the group was still active.  It was a
surreal experience, actually... I thought that "surprise parties"
were something that only happened in movies!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stayed overnight at the house of my married friend in Moriya (a
town nearby to Tsukuba).  The house reminded me slightly of house
of one of my grandparents (the ones in Worcester).  I know that
some North Americans make a big deal about the small size of
Japanese buildings (pun intended), but as far as I can tell,
they're pretty much on par with European houses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Granted, Japanese hotel rooms are smaller than European ones.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="day-11-tsukuba"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Day 11: Tsukuba&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We began the day by jogging around Doho park (a big park close to
my old residence and workplace), then I led 15 minutes of yoga
(because they were curious about it).  That was followed by a free
shower at the park.  (Japan is really clean and orderly!  I can't
imagine a park in Canada offering free heated showers.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lunch was at a vegan restaurant nearby.  I was amused at the
approach they took: "it's good for the environment if you eat
without meat for one or two meals each month".  Clearly they think
that all-round veganism would be an impossible sell in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally saw the JAXA space center!  My research institute was
right next to it, but I never went while I worked there.  I wanted
to go, but I kept on thinking "not this weekend; I'll go later"
and then ran out of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then went to an animal cafe.  Well, more of a "petting zoo"
than a "cafe".  I held a snake, as well as other animals.  Even a
porcupine!  They supplied gloves for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To kill some time before dinner, we wandered around the mall for a
bit, and went to a game center (arcade).  Two of us tried a
Virtual Reality skiing game.  It was unexpectedly terrifying:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You stood in some vaguely ski-shaped tracks, with your hands on
the machine's frame which was shaped like ski poles.  The
position, along with the goggles blocking out exterior light,
makes an &lt;em&gt;incredible&lt;/em&gt; difference in the immersion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That ended up being frightening when the game physics didn't
react the same way I was used to in real life.  Namely, in real
life you can put your skiis at a 90-degree angle to the slope
and come to a stop.  The game didn't let me turn that far, so I
was always pointed (somewhat) down-slope and always accelerating
faster than I wanted.  Even though I knew intellectually that it
was a game, seeing a huge black cliff rushing towards me,
knowing that there was no way that I could avoid it, was hugely
adrenaline-inducing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't get me wrong: I'm very glad that I tried it, and I'm
really looking forward to the future of VR games.  I might even
start going to arcades, because there's no way you can have
multiple different types of games in a home setting (given that
almost every game would need a different type of mechanical
frame)!  But I think that I'll look for games where you don't
"die" quite so often.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For dinner, we tried to go to a restaurant in an old temple which
was famous for its Soba noodles.  But it was sold out -- they only
had sweets left!  So we bought food at a grocery store and ate at
home.  That was another fascinating part of the trip: a normal (or
at least, normal-ish) Japanese evening.  My friend's husband and I
watched TV while the women prepared food.  (Yes, that made me feel
slightly uncomfortable, but it &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; a small kitchen and I'd have
just been in the way, especially given the language barrier and my
unfamiliarity with Japanese cooking.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even the TV show was an interesting experience.  It was a show
where they went around cutting random objects (in a lab setting,
not randomly waving a knife around).  I think I remember them
cutting a piece of quartz, a toilet, an ink seal (these are still
used in Japan instead of a signature for formal documents), a
remote control, and maybe 4 or 5 other things.  After cutting the
object and ceremoniously opening it, they spent 2-3 minutes
talking about how it worked or what the different components were,
then moved onto another object.  In addition to the mechanics who
were operating the blade-saw, they had a panel of people who gave
exaggerated reactions to the objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="day-12-tsukuba-and-narita"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Day 12: Tsukuba and Narita&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I walked around Moriya for a little bit, then took the train to
Tskukba.  My hosts offered to drive me to the station (or to
AIST), but I wanted to see the local sights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granted, "seeing the sights in Moriya" is a little bit like saying
"I want to see the sights in Coquitlam".  Not that either cities
are bad places!  They're both quite... adequate... places to live.
But spending 15 minutes walking to a train station in either city
is nothing like walking 15 minutes in the center of a European
city, or like walking 15 minutes in many other places in Japan.
Not that I regret getting a bit of exercise!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Tsukuba, I wanted to see the new mall that was being built next
to the station 3 years ago (when I left).  Unfortunately, it
didn't open until 10 or 11am, and by that time I wanted to be
elsewhere.  Fortunately, my friends had told me that there wasn't
much to see there (it was generally the same stores that were in
other malls), and looking at the store list from the outside
confirmed that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, I walked around a few parks (Chuo and Matsumi), looked at
my previous local supermarket (SEIYU in DAYZ TOWN), and bought
some stuff at my local 100-yen store (Seriya).  Then I walked past
Ninomiya House and checked out a nearby shoe store.  (My orchestra
shoes came from that store, and my feet are small by North
American stands but only slightly small by Japanese standards.
Unfortunately I didn't find any shoes on sale that suited me,
though.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I walked to AIST (my old research institute), and went through the
security gate and information desk in Japanese.  I was amused that
to gain entry to the building, the first secretary came down to
let me in.  That's quite proper -- I'm a visitor, she's the first
secretary, etc.  But in a less formal setting, I think it would
have been the second secretary that came down to let me in -- I'd
spent the past three day travelling with her, after all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I met my previous boss, chatted about the research lab, and had a
nice meal with them at the research institute's restaurant.  The
group has really expanded in the past three years, and it was
great to see that they were doing so well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, I caught the bus from Tsukuba station to Narita, and
flew back to Vancouver.  My flight wasn't upgraded, but I still
lucked out -- I had an empty seat beside me!  That was my first
time in premium economy, and it was definitely good enough for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="day-13"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Day 13+&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I'd been home for 24 hours or so, I started to get a runny
nose, and after another two days, I realized that I had the flu
and spent the next week in bed.  Oh well -- at least it didn't
happen while I was on the trip!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bunnies</category><guid>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2018-03-19-japan-trip.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 11:31:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Roomba cleaning</title><link>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2018-02-06-roomba-cleaning.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Percival</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I first heard about the Roomba robotic vacuum cleaner, it
sounded like something for the truly lazy -- how hard is it to
spend ten minutes vacuuming your floor once a week?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I tried it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first moved into my condo, I borrowed my brother's Roomba
for a week.  By chance, my parents went on holiday for two weeks
after that, so I borrowed their Roomba.  By that point, I was
hooked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see, it's not a matter of "vacuuming your floor once a
&lt;em&gt;week&lt;/em&gt;".  When I had a robotic cleaner with an easily-cleanable
dustbin, I ran it once a &lt;em&gt;day&lt;/em&gt;.  And that wasn't me being paranoid
-- I emptied that dustbin every day so I could see how much dust
it was removing from my environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After 2.5 years of use, my Roomba started showing a blue starfish
error light, and it made a "clunking" sound as if it couldn't get
into gear.  Time for some serious cleaning!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="cleaning"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Cleaning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(There's a few youtube videos about this floating around, but I
was annoyed at having to watch a 5-minute video to get this info
when a few images and text would have done it just fine.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, remove the yellow brushes (with 1 small screw) and the 4
main screws:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image1" src="http://percival-music.ca/images/roomba-cleaning/roomba-cleaning-1.jpg" style="width: 565.0px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, remove the 4 small screws holding the blue-and-grey "brush
box" and lift it out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image2" src="http://percival-music.ca/images/roomba-cleaning/roomba-cleaning-2.jpg" style="width: 565.0px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now bend the blue arms backwards so that you can pop the grey
plastic out.  There's a wire connecting the back of the blue and
grey part (see the next two images), which you can leave
connected:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image3" src="http://percival-music.ca/images/roomba-cleaning/roomba-cleaning-3.jpg" style="width: 475.0px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is sufficiently detached.  Look at the right-hand side of the
grey box (in the below image).  You want to undo 5 screws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image4" src="http://percival-music.ca/images/roomba-cleaning/roomba-cleaning-4.jpg" style="width: 816.0px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the gear-box!  Looks fairly icky thanks to my long hair:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image5" src="http://percival-music.ca/images/roomba-cleaning/roomba-cleaning-5.jpg" style="width: 500.0px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Close-up of one of the gears.  Some of those gear-teeth are
completely jammed with dust (a bit hard to tell since the dust
reflected the light):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image6" src="http://percival-music.ca/images/roomba-cleaning/roomba-cleaning-6.jpg" style="width: 500.0px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to removing the hair, I also used a small screwdriver
to clean out the gear-teeth.  I happily put the Roomba back
together again -- but the problem persisted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few more disassembly-and-cleaning attempts, it occurred to
em that in addition to removing the hair and dust, I'd also
removed any grease and oil.  I added some bicycle grease, put it
back together, and the Roomba worked perfectly!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I suspect that bicycle grease isn't ideal type of lubricant for
this purpose, but that's what I had easily available to me.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bunnies</category><guid>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2018-02-06-roomba-cleaning.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 20:35:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Revised website</title><link>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2018-01-09-revised-website.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Percival</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;More than five years since the last update!  Yikes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What have I been up to?  Well, I finished my PhD in May 2013, did
two post-doctoral contracts (in Singapore and Japan), then gave up
on academia and returned to Vancouver in May 2015 to work for my
brother's company, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tarsnap.com"&gt;Tarsnap Backup Inc&lt;/a&gt;.
Since then, my main focus has been my health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've made significant changes to my diet, started practicing yoga,
lifting weights, and get at least 7 hours of cardio per week.  I
fell in love with ballroom and swing dancing, and these days I
spend more time dancing than I do on music!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of music, my violin-playing has improved dramatically --
I've played in all four (main) string sections of the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://westcoastsymphony.ca/"&gt;West Coast Symphony Orchestra&lt;/a&gt;
(the best non-professional orchestra in Vancouver), and plan to
play in each section at least once per season.  I'm teaching
violin and cello, and coaching a string quartet.  I've started
composing music again (after a gap of a decade), primarily for my
students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not all good news, though.  I'm still struggling with
perfection-fueled procrastination, a la
"&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Perfect_is_the_enemy_of_good"&gt;Perfect is the enemy of good&lt;/a&gt;").
This website is a perfect example of it: 5 years ago, I decided
that I should switch to a static website generator and stop
writing in raw HTML.  That prompted an incredible number of
hesitations:  Which generator should I use?  Which markup
language?  How can I tweak the markup and/or generator to produce
the HTML I want?  Can I add a CSS file to fix stuff, or must I
edit the template's default CSS, or must I edit the template
itself?  Which web hosting provider should I use?  Does it have
HTTPS?  etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally said "enough is enough", so I'm going ahead with the
revised website right now, despite all the remaining problems.  Or
rather... I said that three days ago.  Even when I started
removing whole sections of the website (e.g., music, teaching,
software), it still took me &lt;em&gt;days&lt;/em&gt; to get this out the door!  My
plan is to make incremental updates to the website, trying to work
with "blocks of time" rather than "perfect chunks of update".
I'll pick some weekly time (say, "Wednesday morning before
teaching"), work on the website, and then upload the latest
version regardless of whether I'm fully satisfied with it or not.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bunnies</category><guid>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2018-01-09-revised-website.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 21:31:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Artifastring 2.0</title><link>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2012-11-22-artifastring-2.0.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Percival</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;After over a year of development, I have released Artifastring 2.0.
This includes higher-quality output, an incredible amount of
optimizations (up to 100x realtime), and now has multiple distinct
instrument sounds: 5 different violins, 2 viola, and 3 cellos.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://percival-music.ca/artifastring/"&gt;http://percival-music.ca/artifastring/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the speed improvements are thanks to the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://eigen.tuxfamily.org"&gt;Eigen&lt;/a&gt; C++ template library for linear
algebra. In particular, this enabled me to easily write SIMD code rather
than using floats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other bits of interest are the realtime OSC server and an interface for
the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://charlie-roberts.com/Control/"&gt;Control (OSC)&lt;/a&gt; app. Users
with iOS or Android tablets can control the physical modelling with
their fingers! I'm hoping to have a video in a few days, although I
still need to find somebody with a video camera. Before you get too
excited, I should add that this is a proof-of-concept of the
communication between tablet and computer; I haven't put any thought
towards the actual GUI or ease of control. My focus is on finishing my
thesis, so if anybody is interested in making better interfaces, go
nuts!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's sure to be rough edges left in this release. I'm trying to force
myself to accept "the perfect is the enemy of the good". I'm having huge
problems writing my thesis because whenever I write down what I've done,
I think of possible flaws, which immediately prompts me to spend a week
or two performing experiments which justify what I've done (or else
demonstrate a real problem, in which case I spend another week or two
changing even more!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, I expect a 2.2 release to happen within the next
month or two. Of course, if more people test the 2.0 version and report
problems, I'll have more confidence (and more motivation!) to get the
2.2 release out there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bunnies</category><guid>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2012-11-22-artifastring-2.0.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2012 01:06:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Ubuntu ssh agent admitted failure</title><link>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2011-08-28-ubuntu-ssh.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Percival</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Ubuntu 10.04 LTS has a serious bug in ssh/ssh-agent/something which
causes it to fail to log in to a system even if you have your ssh
identies set up. This caused me an hour of panic before I found a
workaround. I'm putting it here in case somebody else has the same
problem and google finds this for them. (tl;dr: use
&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;SSH_AUTH_SOCK=0sshfoo.bar.baz&lt;/tt&gt; )&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I swap between two laptops and a desktop regularly. I have a shared
dotfiles git repository, so my normal settings are fine -- but that
won't work for stuff like email passwords, or even email. My current
setup is to use an sd card for personal stuff. (yes, my stuff is in an
encrypted loop-back partition on that card; I'm not crazy!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days ago (just after returning to Glasgow), I started having read
errors on the card. This was particularly sucky because although I'd
bought a new 16gb card while in Vancouver, I hadn't gotten around to
carrying that new card, so I was using my old 8gb card. I was planning
on doing it "soon", but I definitely started to kick myself for not
getting it set up sooner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, it was only about 24 hours since I'd made a backup of the sd
card anyway, and there hadn't been any truly important emails in that
time. (I know the story should go "... but I didn't mind, because I'm
using my brother's tarsnap backup service", but it was actually about 3
days since I'd backed up in tarsnap)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, when I put the card in a different laptop, it read it just
fine. I copied stuff over, checked that things seemed ok, and then
started using the new card regularly. Everything seemed fine for a day
or two, when I discovered that I couldn't log in to various servers. At
this point, I turned to tarsnap to get a backup of my &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;ssh&lt;/tt&gt; directory,
thinking that I'd gotten some freaky bitrot in my private key but
nowhere else. No joy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But wait, it gets worse! Take a look at this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
gperciva@gperciva-desktop:~$ ssh -v strauss.elec.gla.ac.uk
OpenSSH_5.3p1 Debian-3ubuntu7, OpenSSL 0.9.8k 25 Mar 2009
debug1: Reading configuration data /etc/ssh/ssh_config
debug1: Applying options for *
debug1: Connecting to strauss.elec.gla.ac.uk [130.209.179.98] port 22.
...
debug1: Offering public key: /home/gperciva/.ssh/id_dsa
debug1: Server accepts key: pkalg ssh-dss blen 817
Agent admitted failure to sign using the key.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LOLwut? Server accepts key, agent admitted failure to sign in using the
key?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a bit of stumbling around, I found a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://bugs.launchpad.net/ubuntu/+source/gnome-keyring/+bug/201786"&gt;ssh bug
report&lt;/a&gt;
from 2008 in the ubuntu database. Apparently you can work around it by
setting &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;SSH_AUTH_SOCK=0&lt;/tt&gt;. You can also do some weird stuff with
something called "seahorse", but I think I'll just export the variable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bunnies</category><guid>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2011-08-28-ubuntu-ssh.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2011 09:09:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Vampire Rabbit</title><link>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2011-08-23-vampire-rabbit.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Percival</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The is the story of the Vampire Rabbit, and other bits and pieces from
my European vacation from May 2 to 23. Yes, this is a bit overdue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the timing of the first half was unfortunate -- I received the
reviewer's comments about my Vivi paper just before leaving on the
ferry. This meant that I spent the nights (after my traveling companion
had fallen asleep) making typographical corrections, hunting up more
references, and rewriting paragraphs to avoid misunderstandings. Now,
there's a long Percival tradition of doing academic work while on
vacation... but I had hoped that I'd have another 2-5 years before I
fully embraced that life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Processing the photos took a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; longer than I was expecting, and even
then, there's still a lot of mistakes in them. Mispellings (I had at
least two different ways of spelling "Ben Nevis"!), typos, wrong words,
etc. But I've already spent far too long playing with these, so I'm
reminding myself that "the perfect is the enemy of the good" and moving
on. I'll only make a few additional comments to the photos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="scotland"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Scotland&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photos:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011Glasgow"&gt;Glasgow&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011Edinburgh"&gt;Edinburgh&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011Highlands"&gt;Highlands&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011NewcastleSea"&gt;Newcastle and North
sea&lt;/a&gt;
(not scotland, but it fits in this section)&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trip began in Glasgow; my friend arrived from Vancouver. I only got
lost once while looking for the airport bus to go out and get her, but
I'd budgeted sufficient "buffer time" so that I wasn't late. The idea
was that we'd spend a few days in an English-speaking country while she
got over jetlag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We began by walking all over Glasgow (particularly the West End, where
Hogwarts is). Lest anybody doubt that I know how to show a girl a good
time, the necropolis was a big hit. Direct quote: "This is so cool!".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next day we went to Edinburgh, saw the castle, climbed Arthur's Peak,
etc. On the way back to the train station, I wanted to find a washroom,
and we ended up in the Scottish parliament debate chamber. True story! I
saw a sign for the washroom, so we went into the building, and then
security guards kept on noticing that I was looking around and seemed a
bit lost, and they all said "aye, go on around the corner / up the
stairs / through the doors", and there we were.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Driving tour of the Highlands; from Stirling to Fort Williams to Oban to
Stirling again. Saw hills, ocean, sheep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final day in Glasgow: sort out any last-minute stuff for the rest of the
trip. I bought a new travel shaver because my current one had really
dull blades; new shaver was £37 while replacement blades were £44.
Economy: 1, environment: 0? We also saw a junior (12-17 years old?)
chamber music concert. Intonation was better than we expected, but
dynamics and range of expression were worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we took the train to Newcastle-upon-Tyne. Saw the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011NewcastleSea#5635045884068735026"&gt;VAMPIRE
RABBIT&lt;/a&gt;.
Took the DHS overnight ferry to Amsterdam; an unexpectedly swanky trip.
Highly recommended! It was much better than taking an airplane for 2
hours (plus all the travel to/from airport, security, waiting at gates,
etc).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="amsterdam"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Amsterdam&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photos:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011AmsterdamCity"&gt;Amsterdam city
pictures&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011AmsterdamMonuments"&gt;Amsterdam
monuments&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011Kukenhof"&gt;Kukenhof flower
market&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011Leiden"&gt;Leiden&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011AmsterdamZoo"&gt;Amsterdam
zoo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amsterdam, city of bicycles. Deservedly famous for a huge fraction of
the population of the population cycling as their main form of
transportation. Also infamously famous for their red light district,
which my travelling companion insisted on us visiting. (also infamously
famous for marijuana, but since we've from Vancouver that wasn't
particularly notable)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We spent an hour trying to find the red light district. As we were
nearing giving up, we found a McDonalds and Burger King right next to
each other, with red neon signs. We saw the red lights! ... ok, that
wasn't the real place, but I was starting to doubt that it really
existed. We saw five "chinese message" stores. They honestly did have
massage chairs, and in one store there were people doing stuff with
somebody's feet... but I really cannot believe that Amsterdam has such a
huge market for chinese massages that it makes economic sense to have so
many stores in such a small area. I suspected that "chinese massage" was
a euphamism, but my companion insisted that she should be seeing "women
in windows" with red lights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After once again checking our two maps, cross-referencing them with a
printed guide-book, checking the compass, and walking another 15
minutes, we found the red light district. This time, there was no doubt.
It was about 9.30, so getting dark, by the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There really were red lights. I'd thought that "red light district" was
just a phrase, but no -- there were individual "store fronts", lit with
a red neon florescent bulb above the door and window. And in the window
(actually, often the door), was a woman in "underwear". Often shaking or
grinding, sometimes tapping the door to attract attention. It was...
well, the first word that comes to mind is "tacky". Certainly not sexy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, there was one "store front" which attracted my attention --
it did not have a woman cavorting about. Instead, there was a blond
woman sitting on a bed, wearing glases, and reading a book. I'm fairly
certain that the glasses were fake and the "intellectual" facade was a
sham -- but at least somebody was &lt;em&gt;pretending&lt;/em&gt; to be classy. And no, I
didn't see any women with cat ears. Now *that* would have gotten my
attention!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that we didn't make an extensive tour. We passed about half a dozen
windows on our way into the central red light district, and then we saw
a group of seniors in a tour group. We followed them for a bit; this
group was circling a big old chuch smack in the middle of the red light
district. My travelling companion thought that it really was a church
tour group, but I pointed out that if they were honestly there to see
the church, they'd have gone in the daylight, not at night. I mean,
there were red lights just opposite the street from the chrurch, clearly
visible from where they were. After circling the church, we stopped
stalking the senior's travel group, and walked back to our hotel. We
passed another half dozen windows along the way. No, we didn't stop for
any of the live sex shows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, it was more weird than anything else. I didn't feel unsafe
-- granted we left the area before 10pm, but the whole place still felt
quite regulated and well-policed. And I certainly approve of having a
safe place for this kind of thing! But it's not quite my scene, just
like a football match isn't my scene. (I'm sure that the Amsterdam red
light district is much safer than a British football match, though!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day we saw a bunch of museums, and stopped for dinner at a
"bergermeester", where I had a "meester biefburger" with "dragonmayo".
It was absolutely gigantic (even by North American standards!), and I
wasn't certain if I would eat it or if it would eat me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Went to Kukenhof, saw flowers. Not being female, that's about all I can
say about the place. :) After that, we went to the Concertgebouw. Saw a
string quartet, not impressed. They played Haydn like Haydn (clean,
together, careful, fussy, uninspired). The played Beethoven like Haydn.
They played Debussy like Beethoven (some expression, moderate rubato,
taking some risks, not always together but that's ok). No visible
communication between the players; I suspect the Haydn and Beethoven was
really together because they'd played it a lot and knew exactly what
everybody was going to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saw the zoo. Protip: reserve a whole day. We could only spend the
morning there due to train ticket reservations, and regretted it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="brussels"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Brussels&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photos:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011BrusselsCity"&gt;Brussels
city&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011BrusselsMonuments"&gt;Brussels
monuments&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011Bruges"&gt;Bruges&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011Ghent"&gt;Ghent&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011BrusselsMuseums"&gt;Brussels
museums&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011Antwerp"&gt;Antwerp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brussels wasn't as nice as Amsterdam. It's famous for fries (with
mayonaise), but the two or three places we tried fries weren't
particularly special. I mean, they were better than McDonalds fries, but
that doesn't exactly say much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saw the Musical Instrument Museum. That was neat, and they even had a
bunch of old electronic instruments in the basement! That was a very
nice touch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really fancy churches. Protip: if you want to see art, don't bother with
museums or galleries; just wander into a nearby church. Doesn't have to
be a big cathedral; they all have fancy artwork.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did a bunch of short trips to surrounding towns/villages/cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="paris"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Paris&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photos:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011ParisCity"&gt;Paris
city&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011ParisMonuments"&gt;Paris
monuments&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011ParisMuseums"&gt;Paris
museums&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011ParisCemeteries"&gt;Paris
cemeteries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were met at the train station by one of the LilyPond developers. He
very kindly showed us around the town, translated, and gave us the
"inside view" of the city! We got plenty of exercise walking around
Paris.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We met with other LilyPond developers (plus some of their girlfriends --
that is, the girlfriends of some LilyPond developers. I haven't heard of
any of them having more than one girlfriend!). It was really neat
"putting faces to the names".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to seeing the big sites, we visited a cemetery. I really
liked the cemeteries in France when I visited in 1997, so I insisted
that we go to one this time. Not for any kind of macabre reason, or any
kind of "omg this famous person is buried here" reason -- I just like
the fancy graves as pieces of scuplture/architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="south-england"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;South England&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photos:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011EnglandDover"&gt;Dover&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011EnglandDriving"&gt;Miscellaneous pictures from driving
around&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011EnglandRye"&gt;Rye&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011EnglandSteyning"&gt;Steyning&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011EnglandAmberley"&gt;Amberley&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011EnglandSwanage"&gt;Swanage&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011EnglandCorfecastle"&gt;Corfe
castle&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011EnglandLondon"&gt;London&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We met up with a friend and he drove us around southern England,
starting from the ferry to Dover. We stopped to admire a few extremely
picturesque villages and wild ponies, then arrived at the Dorsets area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the morning we saw the really cool &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/107782479450604073806/Euro2011EnglandCorfecastle#5641596765992307426"&gt;Durdle
door&lt;/a&gt;,
then continued driving around, ending up at London for the night. In the
morning, we briefly saw the really big tourist stuff (Buckingham palace,
Westminister Abbey, parliament buildings, big ben, etc).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Returning to Glasgow was a pain. I dropped off my companion at Heathrow
at 14:30, and then took the underground back to London Euston -- only to
discover that the train had been cancelled due to high winds in the
Scottish Borders area! Instead, I was to take a train up to Edinburgh
(from King's Cross), then get a train from Edinburgh to Glasgow. But
halfway along that trip, we were told that the train would end in
Newcastle, and we should wait for the next train (which &lt;em&gt;would&lt;/em&gt; be
continuing up to Edinbrugh).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, I only got back to my flat at midnight. It normally takes
about 5 hours to go from London to Glasgow, not 11.5 hours! But I
arrived eventually, exhausted but happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tentative plan for next year: Berlin, Zurich, Vienna, Prague.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bunnies</category><guid>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2011-08-23-vampire-rabbit.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 12:25:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Becoming social</title><link>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2011-07-13-becoming-social.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Percival</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Following &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://xkcd.com/918/"&gt;xkcd #918&lt;/a&gt;, I have joined google+.
What's google+? To paraphrase that brilliant webcomic, "it's like
facebook, but it's not facebook".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's an important distinction if you have any privacy, moral, or
pragmatic concerns. Facebook is a bad company. Their "walled garden"
approach -- in terms of users' private data, as well as applications and
casual browsing -- does actual harm to the idea of a global internet.
Even if you have no romantic or philosophical notions of the "flow of
information", such walled gardens are simply harmful on a practical
level. When (not if) something unquestionably better than facebook comes
around, you'll lose a lot of data if you use facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(why am I certain that something better than facebook will arrive?
That's simply the history of computing. Every software project is
supplanted eventually; thinking that software XYZ is the pinnacle of
human-computer interaction is the sheerest folly. Something better than
facebook, something better than google+, something better than mutt or
vim or python, is always bound to happen. Maybe not in 5 years or 10 or
20 years, but it &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; happen)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, you can "plus me" (if that's the verb we're going to use)
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://plus.google.com/?tab=XX#107782479450604073806/about"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
Invitations available for people I know who want to join.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bunnies</category><guid>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2011-07-13-becoming-social.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 19:40:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Artifastring 1.6</title><link>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2011-06-27-artifastring-1.6.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Percival</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Artifastring 1.6 is now out. This adds a fancier violin model, scripts
to simplify creating images and video from an .actions file, and a
switch to the autotools build system.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://percival-music.ca/artifastring/"&gt;http://percival-music.ca/artifastring/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were 44 commits between the release-1.4 and release-1.6 tags, with
lots more info in the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/gperciva/artifastring/commits/master"&gt;git
changelog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully this will be the last Artifastring release before Vivi 1.0
(within the next week). After that, expect not much in July. August will
hopefully see Artifastring being expanded to cover cello, viola, and
maybe even multiple violins. This relies on a Masters project at the
University of Glasgow, so it's not under my control.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bunnies</category><guid>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2011-06-27-artifastring-1.6.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2011 20:54:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>ccbeamer 0.2</title><link>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2011-06-26-ccbeamer-0.2.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Percival</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I found a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.hartwork.org/?p=52"&gt;nice set of Creative Commons logos for
LaTeX&lt;/a&gt;, but they were used with
&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;\input{cc_beamer}&lt;/tt&gt;. Following advice in a comment at that blog, I've
turned them into a LaTeX package. Following the spirit of open source --
not to mention the CC-SA license itself -- here's the source code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://percival-music.ca/blogfiles/ccbeamer-0.2.zip"&gt;ccbeamer-0.2.zip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that although the hartwork blog has a general "CC-no derivative
works, unless otherwise expressly stated", the actual zip file states
that it is under CC-SA 3.0.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bunnies</category><guid>http://percival-music.ca/blog/2011-06-26-ccbeamer-0.2.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2011 19:54:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>